Presenter: Good afternoon, and welcome to the programme.
Now, we all know that parents take different approaches to bringing up their kids,
and, thinking of our own upbringing, and people we know,
we all probably have an idea about which styles of parenting we approve of.
We’ve been hearing a lot in the media recently about different parenting styles
– for example, ‘free-range’ parenting,
where children have lots of freedom with not much supervision,
or ‘tiger’ parenting, where parents are very demanding and put a lot of pressure on children to achieve.
In particular,
there’s been a lot of attention given recently to the phenomenon of so-called ‘helicopter parents’
– the ones who hover over their children and control their every waking moment
– and this is generally regarded as a negative thing.
Joining us today is an expert on the psychology of parenting,
who’s going to discuss a new book called Love, Money, and Parenting,
written by economists Matthias Doepke and Fabrizio Zilibotti.
It argues, controversially, that, in fact, in the UK and the USA,
the children of helicopter parents do better at school, are more focused and conscientious,
and are less likely to take risks with drink and drugs.
Hello, Janice, and thank you for coming on the programme.
Janice: Hello.